<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<RequirementsDocument>
    <Metadata>
        <DocumentID>CAT-APP-PLANNING-REQ-v1.0</DocumentID>
        <Title>Cat Travel Planning Requirements</Title>
        <Version>1.0</Version>
        <Status>Draft</Status>
        <Author>AI Interviewer</Author>
        <CreatedDate>2025-07-20</CreatedDate>
        <LastModified>2025-07-20</LastModified>
        <Description>Detailed functional and non-functional requirements for the Cat Travel Planning features of the Cat Travel App.</Description>
        <Stakeholders>
            <Stakeholder role="Product Owner">User</Stakeholder>
            <Stakeholder role="Software Architect">AI Interviewer</Stakeholder>
            <Stakeholder role="QA Lead">AI Interviewer</Stakeholder>
        </Stakeholders>
    </Metadata>

    <Overview>
        <Purpose>This document specifies the functional and non-functional requirements for the Cat Travel Planning features, including finding cat-friendly accommodations and managing travel checklists.</Purpose>
        <Scope>The scope includes features for searching and displaying cat-friendly accommodations, and providing customizable travel checklists with regulatory guidance. Excluded are features related to container management and tracking.</Scope>
        <Assumptions>
            <Assumption>Users are already authenticated.</Assumption>
            <Assumption>Product catalog API for accommodations is stable.</Assumption>
            <Assumption>Redis infrastructure for caching is available.</Assumption>
        </Assumptions>
        <Constraints>
            <Constraint>The app must comply with relevant data privacy regulations.</Constraint>
            <Constraint>Integration with third-party services for accommodation booking will be required.</Constraint>
        </Constraints>
        <Dependencies>
            <DependsOn type="External" system="Accommodation Booking APIs">Integration with external booking platforms for property data.</DependsOn>
        </Dependencies>
    </Overview>

    <Requirements>
        <FunctionalRequirements category="Cat Travel Planning">
            <Requirement id="REQ-CAT-001" priority="High" status="Draft">
                <Title>Search and Display Cat-Friendly Accommodations</Title>
                <Category>Accommodation Management</Category>
                <Description>The system shall allow cat owners to search for and view a curated list of accommodations that explicitly welcome cats, providing detailed information on their pet policies and amenities.</Description>
                <UserStory>
                    <AsA>cat owner</AsA>
                    <IWant>to find and book cat-friendly accommodations</IWant>
                    <SoThat>I can travel with my cat without stress about their acceptance</SoThat>
                </UserStory>
                <AcceptanceCriteria>
                    <Criterion id="AC-001">
                        <Given>I am on the app's home screen</Given>
                        <When>I search for accommodations by location and dates</When>
                        <Then>I should see a list of properties explicitly marked as cat-friendly</Then>
                        <Then>each property listing should clearly display its cat policy (e.g., fees, number of cats, size restrictions)</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                    <Criterion id="AC-002">
                        <Given>I am viewing search results</Given>
                        <When>I apply filters for cat-specific amenities (e.g., enclosed outdoor space, cat-sitting services)</When>
                        <Then>the search results should update to show only properties matching those criteria</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                    <Criterion id="AC-003">
                        <Given>I have selected a cat-friendly property from the search results</Given>
                        <When>I view its details page</When>
                        <Then>I should see comprehensive information about its cat policy, pet-friendly features, and user reviews related to cat stays</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                    <Criterion id="AC-004">
                        <Given>A property has a specific cat policy (e.g., 2 cats max, $50 fee)</Given>
                        <When>I view the property details</When>
                        <Then>The policy details shall be clearly and accurately displayed</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                    <Criterion id="AC-005">
                        <Given>No cat-friendly accommodations are found for the selected criteria</Given>
                        <When>I perform a search</When>
                        <Then>The system shall display a clear message indicating no results were found</Then>
                        <Then>The system should suggest broadening the search criteria or provide alternative options</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                </AcceptanceCriteria>
                <BusinessRules>
                    <Rule id="BR-001">Accommodation listings must be explicitly verified as cat-friendly before being displayed in search results.</Rule>
                    <Rule id="BR-002">Cat policy details (fees, number of cats, size restrictions) must be accurately reflected from the accommodation provider.</Rule>
                </BusinessRules>
                <Dependencies>
                    <DependsOn type="External" system="Accommodation Provider APIs">Integration with external booking platforms for property data.</DependsOn>
                </Dependencies>
                <Notes>
                    <Note type="Technical">Consider caching search results for performance.</Note>
                    <Note type="Business">The definition of "cat-friendly" needs to be clearly established with accommodation partners.</Note>
                </Notes>
            </Requirement>

            <Requirement id="REQ-CAT-002" priority="High" status="Draft">
                <Title>Cat Travel Checklist and Regulatory Guidance</Title>
                <Category>Travel Planning</Category>
                <Description>The system shall provide a customizable travel checklist and comprehensive guidance on cat travel regulations to ensure compliance and safety during journeys.</Description>
                <UserStory>
                    <AsA>cat owner</AsA>
                    <IWant>a comprehensive travel checklist and guidance on cat travel regulations</IWant>
                    <SoThat>I can ensure my cat's safety and compliance during our journey</SoThat>
                </UserStory>
                <AcceptanceCriteria>
                    <Criterion id="AC-001">
                        <Given>I am planning a trip with my cat</Given>
                        <When>I access the travel checklist feature</When>
                        <Then>I should see a pre-populated checklist of common travel items and tasks (e.g., carrier, food, litter, vet check)</Then>
                        <Then>I should be able to add, edit, and remove items from the checklist</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                    <Criterion id="AC-002">
                        <Given>I am planning to travel to a specific destination (e.g., by air, internationally)</Given>
                        <When>I input my travel details</When>
                        <Then>the app should provide relevant information on airline regulations, import/export requirements, and necessary health documents for cats</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                    <Criterion id="AC-003">
                        <Given>I have completed my travel checklist</Given>
                        <When>I select the option to generate a packing list</When>
                        <Then>the app should create a printable or shareable packing list based on my checklist items</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                    <Criterion id="AC-004">
                        <Given>I attempt to add an item to the checklist with an empty name</Given>
                        <When>I try to save the item</When>
                        <Then>The system shall prevent saving and display an error message</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                    <Criterion id="AC-005">
                        <Given>Regulatory information for a specific travel route is unavailable</Given>
                        <When>I request guidance for that route</When>
                        <Then>The system shall inform me that information is unavailable and suggest consulting official sources</Then>
                    </Criterion>
                </AcceptanceCriteria>
                <BusinessRules>
                    <Rule id="BR-001">Pre-populated checklist items should cover essential cat travel needs.</Rule>
                    <Rule id="BR-002">Regulatory guidance must be sourced from reliable and up-to-date official channels (e.g., IATA, government animal health agencies).</Rule>
                </BusinessRules>
                <Notes>
                    <Note type="Technical">Consider a rule engine for dynamic regulatory guidance based on origin/destination.</Note>
                    <Note type="Business">Regular updates to regulatory information will be crucial.</Note>
                </Notes>
            </Requirement>
        </FunctionalRequirements>

        <NonFunctionalRequirements>
            <Requirement id="NFR-PERF-001" priority="High" status="Draft">
                <Title>Application Performance (Cat Travel Planning)</Title>
                <Category>Performance</Category>
                <Description>The application shall provide a responsive user experience for cat travel planning features.</Description>
                <PerformanceMetrics>
                    <Metric name="SearchResponseTime" target="3-5 seconds" condition="for accommodation searches"/>
                    <Metric name="ChecklistLoadTime" target="2-3 seconds" condition="for travel checklist and guidance"/>
                </PerformanceMetrics>
                <TestScenarios>
                    <Scenario>Load testing for concurrent users on search and checklist features.</Scenario>
                </TestScenarios>
            </Requirement>

            <Requirement id="NFR-SEC-001" priority="Critical" status="Draft">
                <Title>Data Security and Privacy (Cat Travel Planning)</Title>
                <Category>Security</Category>
                <Description>The system shall ensure the highest level of security for all user and pet data related to travel planning.</Description>
                <SecurityControls>
                    <Control type="Authentication">All users must be authenticated.</Control>
                    <Control type="Authorization">Users can only access their own pet and travel data.</Control>
                    <Control type="Encryption">Sensitive data (e.g., travel plans, pet health info) must be encrypted in transit and at rest.</Control>
                </SecurityControls>
                <ComplianceStandards>
                    <Standard>Relevant data privacy regulations (e.g., GDPR, CCPA if applicable).</Standard>
                </ComplianceStandards>
            </Requirement>

            <Requirement id="NFR-SCALE-001" priority="High" status="Draft">
                <Title>Scalability (Cat Travel Planning)</Title>
                <Category>Scalability</Category>
                <Description>The system shall be capable of handling a large and growing user base and data volume for travel planning features.</Description>
                <ScalabilityTargets>
                    <Target dimension="ConcurrentUsers" from="1000" to="100000" timeframe="1 year"/>
                    <Target dimension="AccommodationListings" growth="significant" period="yearly"/>
                </ScalabilityTargets>
            </Requirement>

            <Requirement id="NFR-USABILITY-001" priority="High" status="Draft">
                <Title>Usability (Cat Travel Planning)</Title>
                <Category>Usability</Category>
                <Description>The travel planning features shall be intuitive and easy to use, requiring no prior training for core functionalities.</Description>
                <UsabilityMetrics>
                    <Metric name="EaseOfUse" target="simple" task="accommodation search and checklist management"/>
                    <Metric name="TrainingRequired" target="none" condition="for basic operations"/>
                </UsabilityMetrics>
            </Requirement>
        </NonFunctionalRequirements>

        <TechnicalRequirements>
            <Requirement id="REQ-TECH-001" priority="Medium" status="Draft">
                <Title>Platform Compatibility (Cat Travel Planning)</Title>
                <Category>Platform</Category>
                <Description>The application's travel planning features shall be compatible with major mobile operating systems.</Description>
                <TechnologyStack>
                    <Technology type="MobileOS">[iOS]</Technology>
                    <Technology type="MobileOS">[Android]</Technology>
                </TechnologyStack>
            </Requirement>
        </TechnicalRequirements>

        <DataRequirements>
            <Requirement id="REQ-DATA-001" priority="High" status="Draft">
                <Title>Data Retention and Management (Cat Travel Planning)</Title>
                <Category>DataManagement</Category>
                <Description>The system shall manage data retention policies for user and travel-related information.</Description>
                <DataPolicies>
                    <RetentionPolicy dataType="TravelPlans" period="[Configurable]" reason="User preference/Privacy"/>
                </DataPolicies>
            </Requirement>
        </DataRequirements>
    </Requirements>

    <ChangeHistory>
        <Change version="1.0" date="2025-07-20" author="AI Interviewer">
            <Description>Initial version generated from user stories US-CAT-001 and US-CAT-002.</Description>
        </Change>
    </ChangeHistory>

    <Approvals>
        <Approval role="Product Owner" name="[Name]" date="[YYYY-MM-DD]" status="Pending"/>
        <Approval role="Technical Lead" name="[Name]" date="[YYYY-MM-DD]" status="Pending"/>
        <Approval role="QA Lead" name="[Name]" date="[YYYY-MM-DD]" status="Pending"/>
    </Approvals>
</RequirementsDocument>